这是个简单的故事
This is a simple story...
但不易说
but not an easy one to tell.
像寓言  有悲有喜
Like a fable, there is sorrow...
也像寓言  让人不可思议
and, like a fable, it is full of wonder and happiness.
1939年  意大利中部
我唱我所见  没有什么能逃过我的双眼
I sing what I see. Nothing gets by me.
我对混乱说  我在这儿
"Here I am," said I to chaos.
我是你的奴隶  混沌赞  好
"I am your slave!" And he: "Good."
我说  用不着你赞好
"For what?" said I.
我终于自由  比起我的喜悦...
Free in the end, I am! What good is a caress when bliss...
你的赞好  算是什么
this man came to possess?
我已经准备好
Here I am, ready.
像火车般飞驰  然而刹掣不管用
The trains are gone, the brakes are gone.
我再也无法抵抗  迷人的酒神啊  带上我
And I can resist no more. Go, sweet Bacchus, take me.
刹闸不管用  刹闸不管用
The brakes are gone! The brakes are gone!
我听到了
I heard you.
-刹闸失灵了  -踩下去
- No, they're really gone! - Hit the brakes!
我还以为你在念诗
Weren't you reciting a poem?
汽车刹不住
It doesn't work!
刹车
Brake!
我们死定了  树林
We're going to die! The woods!
刹车
Brake!
国王驾到
The king is coming!
国王来了
There he is!
前面人潮涌动  直驶
It's full of people down there. Straight.
刹闸没了
We have no brakes!
我们没有刹闸  挪开
We have no brakes! Move!
美丽人生
LIFE IS BEAUTIFUL
出去走动走动
Go for a walk.
否则明天也到不了
Otherwise, we'll get there tomorrow.
我找到螺丝了
I found the screw.
你现在需要什么
Now what do you need?
没别的  只要让我清静10分钟
Nothing. I need ten minutes alone.
行  我走开
All right, I’ll leave you alone.
要刚才的螺丝吗
Do you want the screw from before?
不要  只要你走开
No, I just want to be alone.
如果找到了颗螺丝  我应该扔掉吗
Do I toss out the screw if I find it?
就让我一个人待10分钟吧
I need ten minutes alone.
那我去洗洗手
I'm washing my hands.
小姑娘  你好
Pretty girl! How's it going?
在干什么
What are you doing?
那些东西是你妈妈的吗
Did your mom put this stuff here?
不  是女房东的
No, the landlady did.
在摆卖吗  好极了
Is it a market? It's beautiful.
这个多少钱  你多大了
How much is it? How old are you?
看来是我问的太多了  你叫什么
I ask too many questions. What's your name?
Eleonora
Eleonora.
幸会  我是Guido王子
Nice to meet you. I'm Prince Guido.
你是王子
Prince?
我真的是王子哦
I'm a prince, I am.
这一带的土地...
All the land...
都是本王子的
all this is mine.
这里是本王子的封邑
Here starts the prince's principate.
我要叫它Addis Ababa
I'll call this place Addis Ababa.
我打算用骆驼取代牛
I’ll change it all. Out go the cows, in come the camels.
骆驼
Camels?
甚至引进几头河马
Even a few hippopotamus.
我要走了  跟公主有约
I must go. I'm meeting with the princess.
-什么时候  -现在
- When? - Now!
早安  公主
Good morning, Princess!
吓死我了  差点没摔死  有没有压伤你
How frightening. I almost killed myself. Did I hurt you?
没啥大事
I've never been better.
你一向都飞身下楼
Do you always leave the house like this?
我想烧黄蜂巢  却被蜇了
I wanted to burn that wasps' nest, but I got stung.
被蜇了  我给你吸吸
A wasp stung you? There? Allow me.
不要动  公主
Hold still, Princess.
黄蜂毒得狠
A wasp's poison is very dangerous.
一定要把毒液啜出来才行
You have to get it out.
-躺下  过会儿就没事了  -谢谢
- Lie down. It’ll take a while. - No, thank you.
-还有哪被蜇了  -没了
- Did you get stung anywhere else? - No, thank you.
好美的景色啊
What a place here! It's beautiful!
鸽子畅游天际  女人从天而降  我一定要搬来
Pigeons fly, women fall from the sky. I'm moving here!
他是这里的王子  他会在这里养满骆驼
It's all his! He wants to fill it with camels! He's a prince!
没错
Exactly.
公主  Guido王子有礼了
Prince Guido at your service, Princess.
我来了
I'm coming!
再见了
Goodbye, then.
我该怎样谢你
How can I thank you?
不用多谢
There's no need.
真想谢的话...
If you really want to thank me...
赏几只蛋来  给我的武士吃
I’ll take some eggs to make a nice omelet for my squire.
随便拿  不要客气
Take whatever you want. It’s all yours.
谢谢
Thank you!
我拿两...六个吧  我来煎个蛋饼
I’ll take two... six. All right? I’ll make a nice omelet.
拜拜  Eleonora  致以诚挚的问候  公主
Goodbye, Eleonora! My regards, Princess.
后会有期
Farewell.
Nuvolari  今晚我们有蛋饼吃
Here I am, Nuvolari! Tonight's special: omelet!
这一带好多骆驼
All camels here!
-哪间屋呢  -转左  快到了
- Where is this house? - Turn left. We're almost there.
你叔叔也跟我们一起住
Is your uncle sleeping with us?
他是酒店的头儿  在酒店都住了30年了
He's lived in the hotel for 30 years. He's the headman.
那间屋子本是他的储藏室  借给我们用的
He's lending us the house. He uses it for storage.
我们到了
There. We're here.
那是我叔叔的马  叫罗宾汉
That's Robin Hood, my uncle's horse.
这是他的马车还有他的房子
Here's my uncle's buggy and my uncle's house.
屋里的那位就是我叔叔了
And inside is my uncle.
叔叔  我们来了  快点  已经很晚了
Hello, dear uncle! Here we are! Hurry, it's late.
汽车途中抛锚了
Here we are. The car broke down!
叔叔
Uncle!
-野蛮人  -他们是谁
- Barbarians. - Who were they?
-只是野蛮人而已  -为何不呼救
- Barbarians. - Why didn't you cry for help?
此时无声胜有声
Silence is the most powerful cry.
你的诗人朋友
Is he your poet friend?
我叫Ferruccio  是搞装修的
My name is Ferruccio. I'm also an upholsterer.
就是这儿  一件旧货仓  地方狭窄  里面堆满了杂物
Here you are. It's an old storehouse full of odds and ends.
我喜欢收藏杂物
An old passion; an odd and end in itself!
收藏来有什么用
What's all this stuff for?
你们要住多久都可以  我可没空陪你们
You can stay as long as you want. It's not easy to be a waiter.
那张床  据说一位革命家睡过
That's the bed. Legend has it Garibaldi slept there.
没什么比非必需品更必需
Nothing is more necessary than the unnecessary.
野蛮人
Barbarians.
市政局在Sestani街  大堂右边
The town hall is on Via Sestani, to the right after the colonnade.
这是浴室  设备略有新意
The bathroom, equipped with the invention of Mr. Bidet.
这里有几本书  诗人传记之类的
There are a few books here, among which The Life of Petrarch.
厨房在这里  脚踏车  也就是单车
The kitchen is in there. This is a velocipede, commonly called a bike.
我要回酒店了  钥匙只有一把  别弄丢了
I have to get back to the hotel. There's only one key. Don't lose it.
欢迎你们的到来  罗宾汉  等等我
It's so good to see you. I'm coming, Robin Hood!
我们走  罗宾汉
你的叔叔很特别
What an uncle!
这个城市多美丽
Look at this!
我没介绍错吧  到了这儿  想做什么就做什么
Didn't I tell you? We're in a city. You can do whatever you want.
没错  无拘无束  想做就做
If you want to do something, you do it.
想放松吗  想大喊吗  喊吧
You want to let yourself go? You want to yell? Yell!
别喊了  发什么神经
Stop it! What are you, crazy?
这是市里  不是乡下
You can't act like you do in the country.
怎么可以大呼小叫
You've been yelling like a madman. You can't yell!
玛莉  钥匙
Mary! The key!
知道了吧  不可以吵嚷
See? You can't yell.
你不应该整天吟诗
Understand? If you stopped thinking so much about poetry...
应该去赚赚钱  令你爸爸放心
you'd make your father happier and you'd make more money than him.
对  Oreste  我正那样劝他
That's right, Oreste. That's what I tell him too.
你应该踏实一点
You have to settle down!
好漂亮的帽子  好看吗
What a nice hat. How does it look?
-真棒  好看吗  -好看是好看  不过这帽子是我的
- Nice. How does it look? - Nice, but it's mine.
我几时开工
When do I start working?
你已经迟到了  赶紧开始吧
You're already late. Right away!
将那椅子搬入工作间
Get that armchair and take it to the workshop.
-那张吗  -对  小心
- That one? - That one. And be careful!
我要去市政局  再见
Good. I'm going to the town hall. Goodbye.
再见  记得规规矩矩
Goodbye, and behave yourselves...
现在时势险恶
because these are hard times.
可不是么
Hard, hard times!
时势险恶
They're hard times?
为啥呀  你有什么高见
Why, what are your political views?
Benito  Adolph  老实点
Benito! Adolph! Be good!
你说啥了
What did you say?
我说  你有什么看法
I said, how are things going?
那么再见了
Goodbye, then.
小心  别撞断椅腿
Careful! You'll break the legs!
再见
Goodbye!
他偷了我的帽子  我不会放过他的
He pulled it off. He took my hat. I'll find him though.
Benito  信不信我赏你一耳光
Benito, you're going to get a slap!
申请书店营业的手续很繁复
I need to do the whole bureaucratic procedure to open a bookstore.
-时间很长吗  -得好几年
- Does it take a long time? - Years.
那就现在填写申请表吧
Then we'd better open a file now.
先填妥申请表  交给政务官签名
First you apply, and the department head has to sign it.
同时...
差点压碎了鸡蛋  昨天才得到的呢
I almost scrambled my eggs. I've had them since yesterday.
我都忘了  幸好没有破裂  你写下来
I forgot about them. Thank God they didn't break. Take note.
本人Guido Orefice兹申请...
I, the undersigned, Guido Orefice...
政务官现在没空签名
- am applying to open… - He can't sign it now!
什么事
What's going on?
我想请你签个名  我要开书店
I need your signature to open a bookstore.
-小姐，发生了什么事  - Rodolfo先生  我告诉过他
- Miss, what's going on? - Mr. Rodolfo, I told him.
-只签一个名  -不签
- Just one signature. - No, I can't.
会有人接替我一小时  问他吧
My substitute will be here in an hour. Ask him.
-就签一下吧  -我们一点休息
- All I need is a signature. - We close at one here!
现在还有10分钟
It's ten to one.
你不服气  尽管投诉
File a complaint.
真黑心  他只要签个名  填份资料
Boy, is he nasty. To sign a paper, open a file,
我就可以立即递申请表
all he had to do was...
却硬要我等一个钟头
Now I have to wait one hour for his substitute.
我要投诉  写下来  本人Guido...
I'm filing a complaint. Write, "I, the undersigned..."
糟糕
What a wallop!
有没有伤到  我帮你
Are you hurt? I’ll help you.
我不是故意的
Come here. I didn't do it on purpose.
别碰我
Don't touch me!
你以后休想开书店
You can forget about your bookshop!
不要戴  有蛋
No, the eggs!
臭小子  我要杀了你
You scoundrel! I’ll kill you!
让开
Out of the way!
早安  公主
Good morning, Princess.
我们能够站着见面就好
I wonder if we'll ever bump into each other standing up.
对不起  我赶时间
Excuse me, but I've got to run.
再见  公主
Farewell, Princess!
-鸡肉  -没问题
- Chicken. - That's easy.
上整只的  鸡屁股向下
It's served whole, bottom down on the plate.
-可以替我切吗  -当然
"Will you cut it for me?" "Naturally."
我抓稳  一刀向鸡膀下捅进去
I stick the blade under the wing
将鸡腿扯掉
then I rip off the drumstick.
然后起鸡胸肉
I cut the meat along the bottom of the breastbone.
-扯掉鸡翅  切掉鸡胸 扒掉鸡皮
- Off go the wings, breast and skin.
龙虾
Lobster
易如反掌
Piece of cake, Uncle.
一刀向虾翼下捅进去...
I stick the wing under the leg.
起虾腿  扭龙虾  一刀...
Off goes the leg. I rip off the lobster, stick the...
龙虾是甲壳类动物
Lobster is a crustacean.
把这甲壳类动物...
Off goes the crust...
起虾壳
of the crustacean.
起虾须  虾须吃不得吧
Off go the crust and antennae. Who eats the antennae?
去掉虾须  去掉龙虾
Off go the antennae, off goes the lobster.
片甲不留
There's nothing left.
没有龙虾  但有色香味美的鸡
We're out of lobster, but the chicken is delicious.
我忘了怎样上龙虾
I don't remember how to do lobster.
直接从厨房捧出来
You serve it as is.
连碰也不用碰
There's no need to touch it!
真容易  难怪我没记住
That's too easy. That's why I didn't remember.
-继续啊  -老实点
- Continue. - Behavior!
在桌旁站定  像这样
Stand by. Still, like this.
-服务员  -在
"Waiter?" "Yes?"
站定  候命  服务员
In position. Stand by behavior. Waiter!
怎么专叫我  怎不叫其他人
Why only me? There must be other waiters, right?
鞠躬  难到哪去
Bowing! Piece of cake.
鞠得再低些
You bow down, further.
像这个香槟瓶  45度
Like this, at a 45 degree angle, just like a champagne bottle.
45度  甚至50度  55度
45 degrees, even 50, 55.
90度  直角  180度
90 degrees. A right angle. 180.
还得鞠多低  180度  像这样吗
How far do I bow down? 180 degrees? Like this?
学向日葵  向日葵向太阳鞠躬
Think of a sunflower. They bow to the sun.
鞠得太低的向日葵...
But if you see some that are too bowed down...
已经枯死  你是侍者  不是下人
it means they're dead! You're serving. You're not a servant.
服务是高精艺术
Serving is a supreme art.
上帝是第一位侍者
God is the first servant.
上帝为人服务  但上帝不是下人
God serves men, but he's not a servant to men.
-没有钮  -傻子  不应该有钮
- There was no button here. - It doesn't go there, silly.
我要把车开回家  还给爸爸  他还得用呢
I have to take the car back to Pop. He's counting on it.
一个月后再开回去吧
You'll take it back in a month or so.
不  我很快就会开回去的  你知道怎么回事吗
No, I've got to get it back soon. You know why?
怎么回事
Why?
-几点了  -你睡着了吗
- What? What time is it? - Were you sleeping?
当然睡着
Of course I was.
你能一边说一边睡
You fell asleep while talking to me!
-你怎么做到的  -叔本华
- How did you do that? - Schopenhauer.
叔本啥
Who?
叔本华  他说过  意志决定一切
Schopenhauer says that with willpower, you can do anything.
我想怎样  就能怎样
"I am what I want to be."
我想睡着  于是说...
Right now I want to sleep, so I was saying to myself...
睡着吧  睡着吧  于是我就睡着了
"I'm sleeping, sleeping," and I fell asleep.
真神奇  也很简单
Amazing. And it's simple too.
我也试试
I want to try too.
睡着吧  睡着吧  睡着吧
I'm sleeping, sleeping, sleeping...
不要动手  现在不是玩杂耍
Don't move your hands. You're not a juggler.
这是思想的功夫  要认真  慢慢来
It's a matter of thought. It's serious, and it takes time.
明天再说吧
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
神奇啊
Amazing, though.
醒过来
Wake up.
又怎样  做什么
What is it now? What are you doing?
-凑效了  -什么凑效了
- It totally works! - What works?
叔本华  我刚刚说  醒过来
Schopenhauer. You know what I just said? "Wake up."
你就立即醒了过来  这理论太不可思议了
Bam, you woke up. This theory is incredible.
-好使吧  -你冲着我的耳朵喊
- How does it work? - You were yelling in my ear!
我能不醒吗
That's why I woke up.
-我该温柔点吗  -根本不该出声
- So I should say it quieter. - Don't say it at all!
好深奥啊
It's deep.
要运用精神力量
You have to think it.
跑什么  慢点
Why are you running? Slow down!
快点  已经迟了
Hurry up. It's late!
玛莉  钥匙
Mary, the key!
每天早晨  她都把钥匙扔下来
Every morning, she throws the key.
看
Look!
那女教师好标致啊
There's that teacher. Boy, is she pretty.
连做梦都梦见她
I even dreamt about her.
来  我给你介绍
Come with me. I’ll introduce you.
-靠  不要动  -怎么了
- Holy smokes! Stay still! - What is it?
不要动
Don't move!
车上的人  是那鸡蛋淋头的混蛋
The one in the car. He's that jerk the eggs fell on.
他见到我  会跟我拼命的
He'll kill me if he sees me. Be good.
-他在干什么  -在说话
- What's he doing? - He's talking.
-说啥呢  -我哪知道
- What's he saying? - How do I know?
-他在干什么  -道别
- What's he doing? - He's saying goodbye.
他的那部车和我的一模一样
He's got a car just like mine!
他来了
There he is!
不要动  他看到我我就死定了
Don't move. He'll kill me if he sees me!
不要动  Ferruccio
Stay still, Ferruccio.
公主早
Good morning, Princess!
又是你  怎会这样巧
It's you again. How do you do this?
是那个从天而降的公主
This is the princess who fell from the sky into my arms.
他是那个替你吸取毒液的人吗
Is he the one who sucked the stinger out of your thigh?
是  我们经常无意碰见
Yes. We keep meeting like this. You just suddenly show up.
我们可以约见
We could make plans to meet.
-今晚八点  -不  还是这样好
- Tonight at 8:00? - No, it's nicer this way.
Dora  我们走  快迟到了
Let's go, Dora. You'll be late.
希望可以再次遇见你
I hope we meet again suddenly.
再见  公主
Farewell, Princess!
见到了吧  她多迷人
Did you see her? She's pretty, huh?
她喜欢我突然出现
She likes it when I suddenly appear.
想不到啊
I don't believe it.
黑暗
"Obscurity."
你是个天才
You're a genius!
越多越看不见
"The bigger it is, the less you see it."
谜底是  黑暗
Solution: obscurity.
了不起
Marvelous.
-你自作的谜语  -不是
- Did you make that riddle up? - No,
你五分钟就猜出来了  我却用了八天
but you solved it in five minutes. It took me eight days.
黑暗
Obscurity!
三文鱼  沙拉  和白酒一杯
Salmon, salad and a glass of white wine.
我再出个谜
Listen to this one, Guido.
不如轮到我出
If I may, it's my turn.
我小时候  听父亲说过
My pop told me this when I was a wee boy.
白雪公主切饼招待七个小矮人
"The dwarves and Snow White sit down for a bite.
白雪公主切饼要切多
How fast can you guess what she serves her guests next?"
相当复杂
It sounds refined.
我现在就试一下
I want to solve it right now.
吃完再猜吧  菜都凉了
Eat first or it'll get cold.
我反正没胃口  时间太晚
I don't want to. It's too late.
沙拉  三文鱼和白酒  都易消化
Salad, salmon, white wine. It's light.
白雪公主...
The dwarves...
和七个小矮人
... and Snow White.
-厨房收了工  -是啊  怎么了
- Is the kitchen closed? - Everybody's gone. Why?
有位视学官从罗马来  想吃东西
A gentleman from Rome is here from the ministry. He wants to eat.
厨师收工了
The kitchen is closed.
他或者会给好多小费
Oh, well, he would have given you a good tip.
厨师开工了
The kitchen is open.
请进
Come right in.
医生  你什么都不吃吗
Doctor, you're not eating anything?
白雪公主和七个小矮人…
"The dwarves and Snow White..."
既然厨房收工了  来点凉菜就行
I know the kitchen is closed. Maybe a cold dish.
敝店菜色精美  请随便点
It's all delicious. Take your pick.
我要清淡一点的
Something light.
我们有巨型牛排
Well, we've got meat, a nice heavy steak...
有羊肉  腰子  酥炸肝
lamb, kidneys, some greasy breaded liver.
-还有鱼呢  -鱼
- Otherwise, there's fish. - Fish.
还有...
We have...
肥美鲮鱼
a nice fatty turbot...
白兰地汁烩香肠酿鳝
eel stuffed with fatty sausage and greased with Grand Marnier...
精瘦的三文鱼
or some lean salmon--
三文鱼  谢谢
The salmon, thank you.
配菜呢
Side dish?
还有配菜呢
There's a side dish too?
任您选择  我们有香炸鲜菇
Of course. We have very, very fried mushrooms...
牛油浓汁炆薯仔
buttered potatoes in Nancy butter with a flaky sauce--
我只要点清淡的沙拉  没有就什么都不要
Is there a small, light salad? If not, nothing.
清淡的沙拉  真可惜啊  香炸鲜菇…
A light salad? What a pity. The very, very fried mushrooms...
滋味无穷  清淡沙拉…
were out of this world. So, a light salad...
瘦三文鱼  一杯白酒
a lean salmon and a glass of white wine.
非常好  请稍等
Perfect. As soon as possible.
我会尽快的
I’ll do my best.
白雪公主多久才切完饼
"How fast can you guess what she serves her guests next?"
没错
Right.
-白雪公主和矮人  -晚安  医生
- The dwarves and Snow White. - Good night, Doctor.
晚安  天才
Good night, genius.
他说什么了  白雪公主  喝茫了吧
What did he say? The dwarves? What is he, drunk?
是个谜语  谜底是”七秒”
It's a riddle. "Seven seconds."
答案是七秒  白雪公主和七个小矮人
"Seven seconds" is the solution. "The dwarves and Snow White."
如果有七个小矮人吃饼
If there are seven dwarves dining...
每人一份的话  总共就是”七秒”
and she serves seconds, that means "seven seconds."
second有”份”和”秒”两个意思
Lessing医生太忠直老实了
Doctor Lessing is a physician, a very serious person.
但他猜谜猜上瘾了  废寝忘食的
But he's obsessed with riddles. He loses sleep over them.
请问方济各学校...
Excuse me. The "Francesco Petrarca" school.
那间小学  我认识那里的一位老师
The elementary school? A friend of mine teaches there. It's beautiful.
离这里不远  怎么了
It's not far from here. Why?
好  我可以睡多半个钟头
Good. I can sleep an extra half hour.
你明早非得去学校不可么
Do you have to go to that school tomorrow morning?
八点半必须到
They're expecting me at 8:30.
各位同学  请安静  我有话说
Please, children, silence! A moment of attention.
视学官很快就要来了
The inspector from Rome will be here shortly.
大家要给他个好印象
I want to make a good impression on him.
他说的话  大家都要用心听
Listen very quietly and carefully to what he says.
他将会报道美丽祖国的大事
He'll tell us some very important things about our beautiful country.
校长  视学官到了
The inspector is here, ma’am.
这么快啊
He's already here? He's early!
坐下  Roberto
Sit down, Roberto!
起立
All rise!
早上好  公主
Good morning, Princess.
早上好  视学官  我是这儿的校长
Good morning, Mr. Inspector. I'm the principal.
这几位是敝校的教员
These are some of our teachers.
好
Good.
那么...
Therefore...
你在本区任教多少年了
How many years have you taught in this school district?
16年
Sixteen.
教育部今年通过的教育方案...
Are you up to date with the ongoing...
你有没有好好领会
school program approved by the ministry this year?
有
Yes.
有没有阅读学童保健通告
Did you read the bulletin regarding childhood hygiene?
当然有
Of course.
你星期天都干什么
What are you doing on Sunday?
我说的星期天是指…
No, I mean, Sunday is…
圣母节  你都做什么
St. Mary's Day. What are you doing?
去剧院
I'm going to the theater.
-看什么  - Offenbach
- To see what? - Offenbach.
对  正在上演Offenbach
Right, they're playing Offenbach.
好  那么…
Fine. Well...
十分感谢  再见  我是来...
Thank you very much, and goodbye. I just came to--
我们知道
We know.
最近  我们和罗马来的视学官...
As you know, the inspector...
还有意大利最权威的科学家
came from Rome to talk to us about the race manifesto...
联合发表了一份种族宣
signed by the most well versed Italian scientists.
我们深感荣幸
He will, and we're very honored,
视学官会说明  我们的种族...
demonstrate to us that our race
是普天之下...
is…
最优越的种族
the best of all.
大家坐
Take your seats.
视学官  您请
Go ahead, Inspector.
-我们的种族...  -是最优越的
- Our race-- - Is superior.
那是当然
Naturally!
我们的种族是最优越的
Our race is superior.
小朋友  我老远从罗马来...
I've just come from Rome, right this minute...
是要教导你们  我们的种族
to come and tell you in order that you'll know, children...
是最优越的种族
that our race is a superior one.
我被...
I was...
意大利的种族主义科学家...
chosen, I was, by racist Italian scientists...
选中  来证明
in order to demonstrate...
我们种族的优越性
how superior our race is.
孩子们  他们为什么偏偏选中我呢
Why did they pick me, children?
问得多余
Must I tell you?
比我更英俊的男子...
Where can you find...
试问世间有没有
someone more handsome than me?
当然没有
Justly so, there is silence.
我是纯正日耳曼人  最优越的种族
I'm an original "superior race".
或许有人问...
Let's start with something that one says:
你怎么优越了
"What's so big about that?"
耳朵  看看这耳朵多么完美
The ear. Look at the perfection of this ear.
一弯耳轮...
Left auricle...
末端垂着耳珠  像个小铃铛
with a pendant little bell at the end.
精巧的软骨  活动自如
Check it out. Movable cartilage.
可伸可缩
Bendable.
有这样的美耳  舍我其谁
Find two ears more beautiful than these and I’ll leave!
你们找到另一对  我就卷铺盖走人
But you have to show me them. They dream about these in France!
世间有不同种族  理所当然
Races exist, children. You bet they do!
继续  还有别的  我来示范
But let's continue. I want to show you something else.
大家留神
Pay attention.
他自称  视学官
He said Inspector?
从罗马来
From Rome?
肚脐
The belly button!
看吧  脐带绑得多巧妙
Take a look at this belly button! What a knot!
而且解不开  用牙咬也咬不开
But you can't untie it, not even with your teeth!
种族主义科学家想解  只是妄想
Those racist scientists tried it. Not a chance!
这意大利肚脐  属于我们的种族
This is an Italian belly button. It's part of our race!
欣赏一下我的体形
Check out this style!
看看这些肌肉
Look at these muscles:
单头肌  二头肌  三头肌
ceps, biceps, triceps!
美仑美奂  见识见识这臀部
Look at this beauty! Admire this hip!
婀娜多姿
Just look at the movement!
诸位
Gentlemen!
我要道别了
I must say goodbye now.
不得不走  有约要赴
I have to go. I have an appointment.
我要告辞了  日耳他式的高贵离场
I’ll make my Aryan exit and bid you farewell.
后会有期  大家保重肚脐
Farewell! The belly button!
在威尼斯见  公主
I’ll see you in Venice, Princess.
我只能用这对耳朵才听得到
I can only hear out of this ear.
望过来吧  公主
Look at me, Princess.
望过来  我在这里
Go on, I'm down here.
望过来吧  公主
Look at me, Princess.
转过头来  公主
Turn around, Princess.
转过来  转过来
Turn around, around...
-我们想吃巧克力冰激凌  -那要快点吃
- Can we get a chocolate ice cream? - Yes, but we'll have to be quick.
为什么
Why?
局长约了我们八点去吃饭
We have to be at the prefect’s at eight. We were invited to dinner.
-在哪  -局长官邸
- Where? - At the prefect’s.
这下惨了  希望这不是真的
Have pity on me, Lord. Let it not be true.
又要去应酬他
Another dinner at the prefect’s?
你母亲也去
Your mother is coming too.
惨
Bingo!
一起去吧  喝杯咖啡  坐一坐就走
Let us just go to dinner. We'll stop by the prefect’s for coffee.
我不去
I'm not coming!
你不想去是吧  那我推掉他算了
All right, I heard you! I’ll tell him we're not going.
我们俩个去别的地方吃吧
It’ll just be me and you.
-你好  Rodolfo  -你好  局长
- Good evening, Rodolfo! - Good evening, Mr. Prefect.
记得八点钟来我家
I’ll see you later at my house. I’ll expect you at 8:00.
我们会准时到
We'll be there at 8:00 sharp.
她在哪里  你看见了吗
Where is she? Did you see her?
-必定在这里  -你来了
- She has to be here. - You're here?
明天准时  知道吗
On time tomorrow, got it?
有没有把那匹布搬下车
Did you take that stuff out of the car?
是丝绸  小心  不要刮花
It's silk. Don't ruin it. Be very careful.
-这出戏真好看  -精彩
- What an opera. - Beautiful!
布帘是你的吗
Is that one of your curtains?
不  是我同事的
No, it must be one of my colleague's.
他又怎么又偷我帽子
He took my hat again!
-我们走  -你没看见外面下雨呢吗
- Let's go. - Don't you see how it's raining?
-你把车开过来  -就在附近
- You go get the car. - It's right around the corner.
好  你在这里等
All right, you wait here.
我会开过来  然后按喇叭
I’ll pull up right here and toot.
钥匙拿来
Give me the key!
不是门钥匙  是车钥匙
Not the house key! The car key!
车钥匙  你有病啊
The car key? Are you crazy?
那个鸡蛋淋头的混蛋...
Keep him busy, you know, the jerk the eggs fell on.
你去尽量拖住他  我们晚上见
Keep him busy as long as you can. I’ll see you tonight.
车上坐着…  慢点开
Inside the car there's... Go slow!
你起码应该带把雨伞来
The least you could have done is come get me with the umbrella.
你一点风度都没有  看  给我弄得多狼狈
You're just plain rude. Look what a mess I am.
还要我应酬局长  好不自在
Plus, dinner at the prefect's gets me so nervous!
如果我感到不自在...
I knew it. I've got the hiccups.
我一定打嗝
I always get them when I'm made to do something I don't want to.
其实我没有什么别的要求
Don't you know that it takes so little to make me happy?
一两杯巧克力冰激凌  我就满足了
A chocolate ice cream is enough! Even two!
大家散散步  自自然然
A nice walk together and then whatever happens happens.
可是你却...
Instead you...
早安  公主
Good morning, Princess!
又是你  你应该向我解释
This is incredible. You owe me an explanation.
不  你才应该向我解释
No, you're the one who owes me an explanation!
你从天而降  落入我怀里
I stop under a roof and you fall from the sky into my arms.
我从单车摔下  摔进你的怀里
I fall off my bicycle and end up in your arms.
我去巡视学校  又碰到你
I do an inspection at school, and there you are again!
我连做梦都梦见你
You even turn up in my dreams.
让我清净清净行不行  你对我太痴缠
Will you leave me alone? You've really got a crush on me.
也难怪  不过...
I don't blame you, but...
好吧  我投降  你赢了
All right. At this point, I give in. You win.
我们到哪去  海  喜欢海吗
Where shall we go, Princess? To the sea! Do you like the sea?
载我回剧院吧  有人等我呢
Yes, but they're waiting for me at the theater. Take me back.
什么事
What's happening?
公主  知道怎么开雨刷吗
Princess, do you know how to turn on the windshield wipers?
刹车
Step on the brakes!
不用怕  坐稳了
Have no fear! Hang on to me!
方向盘坏了
It's broken!
你什么时候学的开车
When did you learn to drive?
-10分钟前  -没到10分钟吧
- Ten minutes ago. - I thought it was less than that.
-车顶关不上  -车门打不开
- The top doesn't close. - The door won't open.
我们困住了
Wait! We're stuck!
一定出得去  放心
We'll get out of here. I’ll take care of it.
重要的是  你别淋湿了
The important thing is that you don't get wet.
挡上点
Cover yourself with this.
拿着  我们走
Take it. We'll get out of here now.
有我呢  放心
I’ll take care of everything.
扶稳
Here we go.
出来吧  公主
Step right out, Princess.
出来吧
There! Step right out!
等等  有一潭水  别弄湿了你的脚
There's a huge puddle! You'll get your feet wet! Wait!
行
Here!
-走吧  -我们在哪
- Go ahead, Princess. - Where are we?
在旧地重游
We've already been here.
你我到过  几时
Me and you? When?
你忘了?
Don't you remember?
那晚下着雨
The night it was raining...
我用枕头给你遮雨
and I made you an umbrella out of a pillow!
夜色迷人  我托着方向盘...
It was a beautiful night. I put the steering wheel on my shoulder...
翩翩起舞  舞至你面前
did a little waltz, and when I stopped in front of you...
你赏我一吻
you kissed me.
公主  后面风大  小心着凉
Princess, your behind is blowing in the wind.
我只听我喜欢的人的话
It depends on the person. My pop was like that.
爸爸生前  我肯听他话
He had the ability to make me do anything.
他了解我  懂得和我相处
He understood me. He knew how to deal with me.
我就像他膝头的小狗狗
I was like putty in his hand.
从不拒绝
I always, always, always said yes.
也就是说  你这个百宝箱...
So, all these treasures you're hiding,
一但打开  你就千依百顺
there is a way to open this treasure chest
从不拒绝
and always get you to say yes!
你找到适合的钥匙就行
All you need is the right key.
怎样找到
And where exactly is it?
天晓得
Heaven knows.
云散了
It's clearing up.
你是说…
So, you were saying...
那把钥匙必定从天而降
the key that always makes you say yes has to come from heaven.
对
Yes.
我要试试
I’ll give it a try.
说不定圣母玛莉会赏给我
lf the Virgin Mary tosses it down to me...
说不定呢
You never know.
Mary  钥匙
Mary, the key!
是这把吗
Is this it?
真要回家  不吃巧克力冰激凌吗
Do you really have to go home? What about the chocolate ice cream?
-现在去吃吧  -现在不行
- Let's get it right now. - No, not now.
-那要什么时候  -不知道
- Then when? - I don't know.
又是天晓得
Are we going to let heaven decide that too?
不要再为小事麻烦Mary了
No, leave Mary alone. Don't bother her over an ice cream!
什么时候吃冰激凌  不是小事  是大事
No, it's way too important. We can't decide when to have it.
我一定要问她
I have to ask her.
Mary  派人来通知
Mary, send someone to find out...
什么时候能吃上冰激凌
how long before we can have the ice cream!
七秒钟
Seven seconds!
-这是我的家  -我经过了千百次
- This is my house. – I've gone by here a thousand times.
每次都自忖  谁现在住在这儿
I’ve always asked myself: Who lives there?
我想在对街开间店铺
I wanted to open my store right out front.
-书店  -对  可以天天见到你
- The bookshop? - Yes. I’ll see you every day.
再见
Goodbye then.
你对我很好  我现在只想洗个澡
You've been so nice to me. All I want now is a hot bath.
我还有句话想说
I forgot to tell you.
说吧
Go ahead.
你想像不到  我多渴望和你做爱
You can't imagine how much I feel like making love to you.
但我绝不会告诉任何人  尤其是你
But I’ll never tell anyone, especially not you.
除非严刑逼供  否则我绝对不说
They'd have to torture me to make me say it.
说什么
Say what?
说我想和你做爱
That I want to make love to you.
不仅做一次  是做完又做
Not just once. Over and over again!
除非我神经错乱
But I’ll never tell you that.
否则不会透露  我渴望和你做爱
I'd have to be crazy to tell you I'd even make love to you now...
现在就想做  做足一生一世
right here, for the rest of my life.
又快下雨了  你还是快走吧
You'd better run or you'll get wet. It's going to rain again.
公主
Princess.
你湿透了
You're all wet.
西装湿了就湿了吧
My suit is no big deal.
帽子湿了才不舒服
It's that hat that bothers me.
我要顶干帽子  哪里有呢
I need a dry hat, but where can I find one?
你刚才用的方法  我有样学样
How did it go? Right, it's easy!
Mary  派人送顶干帽子给他
Mary, send someone to give my friend a dry hat.
晚安  公主  再见了
Good night, Princess. Farewell.
请问洗手间在哪里
Excuse me, where's the restroom?
直走  左手边
Straight ahead to the left.
你再不起床...
If you don't get up immediately...
我在你亡父灵前发誓  再不理你
I swear on your father's deathbed I’ll never speak to you again.
再也不搭理你
For the rest of my life!
我数三声
I'm going to count to three now.
你再不起床  我就把你拽起来
lf you don't get up, I’ll force you to get up.
一
One...
二
two...
三
and three.
好孩子
Good girl.
知道谁快要结婚了吗
Do you know who's getting married?
鸡蛋淋头的混蛋
Didn't I tell you? That jerk the eggs fell on!
-娶谁  -不知道
- Who's he marrying? - I don't know.
新娘还未出现
But she hasn't even shown up yet.
人人都在等着
Everybody's waiting.
找你找得好辛苦
I've looked everywhere for you!
-你叔叔  -我叔叔
- Your uncle. - My uncle?
他出事了  跟我来
Something's happened. Come with me!
到外面  马
Outside! The horse!
什么事
What's that?
那是你的马
Is that your horse?
真见鬼  上面涂着什么
What a sight! What did they write on him?
小心  犹太马
"Achtung, Jewish horse."
都是那班野蛮人做的好事
The usual barbarians, vandals. It's sad. What nonsense.
犹太马
"Jewish horse"!
不要生气  他们只是…
Don't get upset. They just did it to...
这不是孤立的事件
They didn't do it to... They did it "to."
你要习惯一下
You'll have to get used to it, Guido.
他们也会找你麻烦
They'll start with you too.
找我麻烦  怎样找
With me? What could possibly happen to me?
顶多把我剥光  给我染黄  涂上...
The worst they can do is undress me, paint me yellow and write...
小心  犹太侍应
"Achtung, Jewish waiter."
不说不知  原来这匹马是犹太马
I didn't even know this horse was Jewish.
走吧  明早我会把马洗干净
Let's go. I’ll clean him up in the morning.
牵它回马厩
Take him back to the stall.
看  你前面
Look, there, in front of you!
等一下  我想给她一个惊喜
Wait. I’ll surprise her.
来  我介绍Fido Giovanardi给你认识
Come with me. I'd like to introduce you to Fido Giovanardi.
Lessing医生  到哪里去
Doctor Lessing! Where are you going?
我接到急电  要立即回柏林
Urgent telegram. I must go to Berlin immediately.
-为什么拿着盘花  -为你践行
- What are these flowers? - They're for your departure.
我只要一枝
I’ll take just one.
我会跟我妻子说  Guido送的花
I’ll take it to my wife: Guido's flower.
和你交友  是人生一快
I truly enjoyed myself with you.
你是一位...
You're the most ingenious...
很有才智的侍者
waiter I've ever come across.
哪里  你是一位很有修养的顾客
Thank you. You're the customer with the most culture I've ever served.
哪里
Thank you.
再见  Lessing医生
Goodbye, Doctor Lessing.
猜猜这个谜
By the way.
一提起我...
"lf you say my name...
我就消失  我是谁?
I'm not there anymore. Who am I?"
一提起我  我就消失
If you say my name, I'm not there anymore.
什么  他说什么
What is it? What did he say?
谜底  沉默
"Silence!"
妙  一说那字  字就消失  沉默
Beautiful. If you say the word, it's not there anymore. Silence.
我说的不是大都会  是乡下
I'm not talking about Berlin, in the outskirts. Imagine that!
三年级学生  听好了
Third grade. Listen to this problem.
我记得这题是因为它难住过我
I remember it because it shocked me.
国家每养一疯子  每日花4马克
A lunatic costs the state four marks a day.
每养一瘸子  4.5马克
A cripple, four and a half marks.
癫痫患者  3.5马克
An epileptic, three marks and a half.
这些废人人数达30万
Considering that the average is four marks a day...
设  国家平均每人每日花4马克
and there are 300,000 patients, how much would the state save...
将他们全部除掉  可节省多少
if these individuals were eliminated?
真离谱
I can't believe this!
我也觉得离谱
That was my exact reaction.
七岁小孩
I can't believe a seven-year-old child...
怎么算得出来
has to solve this kind of equation.
想计算出来  要略懂比例...
It's a difficult calculation. Proportions, percentages.
略懂百分率  还要略懂代数
They need at least some algebra to do those equations.
这是中学的数学啊
That's high school material for us.
用乘法就行  有30万个废人吗
No, all it takes is multiplication. You said there are 300,000 cripples?
30万乘以4
300,000 times four.
全部除掉  每日节省一百二十万马克
If we killed them all, we'd save 1,200,000 marks a day.
很容易嘛
It's easy!
说得对
Exactly!
但你是成年人  他们是七岁小孩
But you're an adult. They make seven-year-old children do this in Germany!
德国人的确是另一个种族
It's truly another race.
早安  公主
"Good morning, Princess."
-你说什么  -蛋糕上的字
- What did you say? - It's here, on the cake.
不要呆若木鸡
Why are you just standing there? Let's go!
去跳舞吧
Let's dance.
我简单说几句
Just a few words. You already know it all by now...
你们已经非常了解
and you've known for several years.
我和Dora生在同一条街
Dora and l were born on the same street.
上同一间学校  交同一群朋友
We went to school together, we had the same friends.
今生  我非Dora不娶
Dora is the woman of my life...
Dora也非我不嫁  所以
and I'm the man in her life, therefore...
我们决定今年结婚
we've decided to get married within the year.
恭请各位亲友  四月九日...
You're all officially invited on April the 9th...
到巴西里加圣玛莉感恩教堂观礼
to the Basilica of Santa Maria del Pellegrino.
然后来这里  一起通宵庆祝
And then we'll celebrate till dawn all together, right here...
像现在一样  喜气洋洋
just as happy as we are now.
亲亲未来新娘
Kiss her! Kiss her!
-有什么不对劲 -没有
- What's wrong with you? - Nothing.
-你没事吧  -没事
- Are you all right? - Fine.
谁把椅子放这里的
Who put this armchair here?
你没事吧
Are you all right?
-我没事  -我很遗憾
- I’m fine. - I'm sorry.
-我没受伤  -我是指...
- I didn't get hurt. - No, l was talking about--
-玩得开心吗  -不错
- Are you enjoying yourself? - It's going fine.
回到你那桌去
Go back to your table.
走吧  我会清理的
Go on. I can do this.
-你没事吧  -我很好
- Are you all right? - Fine!
人人都问我有没有事  为什么
Why are you all asking me that? Is there something wrong?
没什么
No, nothing is wrong.
可是…
But...
到厨房去
Go to the kitchen.
The kitchen.
今晚所有的东西都搬走了
They moved everything around tonight.
厨房也搬了  看
Look where they put the kitchen.
猜猜谁来了
Peekaboo! Guess who?
是我呀  怎么没反应
It's me! What, have you gone soft?
小姐
Miss.
终于有幸见面  Dora
We finally meet, Dora.
他不会介绍  你没胆介绍吧
He never introduced us. You were scared to, weren't you?
以后你不用跟我们上妓院了
Now you don't need to come with us to the brothel anymore!
打扰打扰  恭喜恭喜
I apologize if I've disrupted you. Happiness and best wishes to all.
你这老滑头
You sly old dog!
多么风趣的人
What a jolly fellow!
没事  我会清理的
Everything is just fine. I’ll pick it all up.
对不起
I apologize.
公主
Princess!
你也在这里
You're here too?
带我走
Take me away.
各位嘉宾
And now, ladies and gentlemen...
本酒店酬谢惠顾  谨致送贺礼
a magnificent surprise offered by the Grand Hotel.
伊塞俄比亚式蛋糕
The Ethiopian cake!
谢谢  请奏乐
Thank you! Music, maestro!
-恭喜恭喜  -谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
谢谢
请上马  公主
Right this way, Princess.
你似乎是...
But you're...
快点  公主
Quickly, Princess.
他似乎是...
But he's...
他是那个鸡蛋流氓
He's that jerk with the eggs!
Ferruccio
Ferruccio!
门钥匙在他那儿  真倒霉
He's got the keys to the house, darn it all!
铁线  有铁线我就打得开
Some wire. I can open it if I find some wire.
我是铁线能手  家传绝技
I'm a whiz with wire. My pop taught me.
小时候  我用铁线做玩具
l used to make toys out of wire when l was a kid.
开了
l opened it.
Joshua
Joshua!
我们走  妈妈等着呢
Let's go. You're going to make Mommy late.
我的坦克丢了
I lost my tank.
放心  我们会找到的
Don't worry. We'll find it.
放哪儿了
Where did you leave the tank?
-楼梯上  -我去拿
- It's on the stairs. - I'll get it.
抓稳  我去拿
Hold the bicycle. I'll get it.
坦克
Here.
起程
Let's go.
-爸爸  加油  -慢点
- Go, Pop! - Go slow!
你上课要迟到了
You're late for school! Go!
有匹马  两匹
There's a horse! Two horses!
不要按铃  吵死我了
Stop ringing that bell! It's driving me mad!
-不是我  是Joshua  -不是我  是爸爸
- It's not me. It's Joshua. - It's not me. It's Pop!
让我下车
Stop it! Let me off!
到了
Here we are.
今晚见
See you tonight.
爸  踩快点
Go fast, Pop!
可以买个饼给妈妈吗
Can we buy this for Mommy?
-多少钱  -15里拉
- How much does it cost? - Fifteen lire.
可能是个假饼  就像你的坦克
It's a fake. It's probably a fake cake, like your tank.
我们走吧
Let's go, Joshua.
犹太人与狗...
"No Jews or dogs...
不准入内
allowed."
为什么犹太人与狗不准入内
Why aren't Jews or dogs allowed to go in?
他们不欢迎犹太人和狗
They just don't want Jews or dogs to go in.
各有各喜恶
Everybody does what they want to.
那里有间五金店铺
There's a hardware store there.
不欢迎西班牙人和马进去
They don't let Spanish people or horses into his store.
再前点  有间药房
Further ahead, there's a drugstore.
有个中国人想拖着袋鼠进去
I was with a Chinese friend of mine yesterday who had a kangaroo.
我说  我们能进去吗  华人与袋鼠  不准入内
I said, "May we?" "No, we don't want any Chinese or kangaroos here."
店主不欢迎  有什么办法
They don't like them. What can l tell you?
我们的书店谁都欢迎
We let everybody into our bookshop.
不  从现在起  我们也要竖个牌
No. From now on, we'll write it too.
-你不喜欢什么  -蜘蛛  你呢
- Is there anybody you don't like? - Spiders. What about you?
我不喜欢西哥特人  明天竖个牌
I don't like Visigoths. Starting tomorrow we'll write...
蜘蛛与西哥特人  不准入内
"No spiders and Visigoths allowed."
最讨厌就是西哥特人
I'm sick and tired of these Visigoths.
早安
Good morning.
全部半价
Everything's half price.
-Guido Orefice
- Guido Orefice?
正是我
That's me.
请到市政局去
You have to come to the prefect's.
又要去
Again?
-他去过  -走吧
- He already went. - Let's go.
为什么
Why?
-那人跟你一起  -是  走吧
- Is that man with you? - Yes. Let's go.
行
All right.
我也去
I'm coming too.
不要去  我不会去太久  对吗?
No. You stay here. It won't take long, will it?
很快回来
Not long at all.
Joshua  好好招呼客人
Joshua, make sure you treat the customers good!
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
我要这本书
I'll take this one.
5里拉
It costs five lire.
上面写着10里拉
No, it says ten lire.
全部半价
Everything's half price.
交给你妈妈  告诉她...
Give this to your mom and tell her…
是外婆的
it's from Grandma.
我从未见过外婆
I've never seen my grandma before.
想见吗
Would you like to meet her?
想
Yes.
你明天就见得到
You'll meet her tomorrow.
-明天  -嗯
- Tomorrow? - Yes.
因为明天是你生日
Because tomorrow is your birthday...
你外婆会带份大礼来
and your grandma will come and bring you a nice present.
新的坦克
A new tank?
不  令你惊喜的礼物
No, a surprise.
把这封信交给你妈妈
Give the letter to your mom.
拜拜  Joshua
Bye, Joshua.
外婆  你零钱落了
You forgot your change, Grandma.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你什么时候回来  -一个钟头左右
- When are you coming? - In an hour or so.
我去找叔叔  或者他那里有剩饭
I’m going to stop by my uncle's to see if he'll bring some leftovers.
-外婆怎么说  -她明天来
- Then what did Grandma say? - She's coming tomorrow.
早就该来
It's about time!
犹太店铺
JEWISH STORE
-该你洗澡了  -我不想洗
- It's time for your bath now. - I don't want to take one.
-去洗澡  -我星期五洗过
- Go take a bath. - I took one on Friday.
他说得对
He's right.
你去换衬衫
You change your shirt.
-我星期四换过  -别忘记把花摘掉
- I changed it on Thursday! - Don't forget the flowers!
还在外面  我已经摘了
They're outside. I already picked them.
-我也去  爸爸  -你要洗澡  小顽固
- I'll come with you, Pop! - You have to take a bath, stubborn!
就不洗
I don't want to take one!
快点  我要去接外婆
Hurry up. I have to go pick Grandma up.
-想把鲜花放在哪   -放下  我等会插
- Where do you want the flowers? - Set them down. I'll be right there.
我星期五洗过
l took one on Friday!
Joshua呢
Do you know where Joshua is?
一定在房里
He must be in there.
收拾一下好吗
Will you put those things in order?
花很漂亮  拿来给我看看好吗
Why don't you show me the flowers? They look so beautiful.
是很漂亮  你要看吗  我给他们拿过来
They are. I'll bring them right over. You want to see the flowers?
这就拿过来
I'll make them come right over.
来吧  花朵
Come, flowers!
来吧  小柜
Come, nightstand!
Schopenhauer  意志力  小柜来
Schopenhauer, willpower, I want the nightstand to come here.
小柜来
Nightstand, come.
小柜停
Stop, nightstand!
小柜不洗澡  好脏
The nightstand seems very dirty to me.
早安  公主
Good morning, Princess!
他已经识字了吗
He can already read and write?
-识了一年了  -你教得真好
- For over a year now. - You did a good job.
我们到了
We're here.
我扶你下车
I'll help you get out.
我自己可以
No, l can do it myself.
Dora  什么事
Dora, what's wrong?
我们到了没有
Are we there?
没有  到了十字路口
No, it's a crossing.
我们究竟要到哪去
Will you tell me where we're going now?
到哪去  什么意思
What do you mean, where?
你都问过好多次了  我们要去...
You asked me a thousand times. We're going...
一个地方  那地方叫什么来着
to the place... What's it called?
我们要到...
We're going...
要到哪里去
Where are we going?
今天是什么日子  你的生日啊
What day is it today? Today is your birthday!
你一直说  你想旅行
You've always said you wanted to go on a trip!
为了这趟旅行  我筹备了好几个月
It took me months to plan this whole thing.
知道我们到哪里去吗
You know where we're going?
我答应了妈妈  不能说
I can't tell you. I promised Mom I wouldn't tell.
说出来  她会生气的
You know how she is. She'll get mad.
总之保证你会满意
It makes me laugh.
我小时候  爸爸也计划了一次旅行
My pop planned something like this for me when l was little too.
真的好…  好好玩
It was so... Boy, it was funny!
先不告诉你
I'm not going to tell you.
等你自己看看
I want you to see for yourself.
给你来个惊喜
It's a surprise. You know, it's really...
保证你满意
It really makes me laugh.
我累了
I'm tired.
睡觉吧
Go to sleep.
他们带我们到哪处去
Where are we going? Where are they taking us?
现在几点了  我们准时出发
What time is it? We're leaving right on time.
多么有效率啊
What organization!
-你没坐过火车  -没有  很棒吗
- You've never taken a train, huh? - No. Is it nice?
很棒
It's really nice!
里面全部是木造的  人人都站着
It's all wooden inside. Everybody stands up.
没有座位
There's not one seat.
-一个座位都没有吗  -火车怎会有座位
- There aren't any seats? - What? Seats on a train?
你真土  没坐过火车吧
It's obvious you've never been on one!
人人都要站着  挤得很近
No, everybody stands real close together.
见到这条长龙了吗  我刚刚抢到了票
Do you see this line? I got the last tickets just in time!
Eliseo叔叔  快点  否则赶不上了
Hurry up, Uncle Eliseo.
我不想听到他们说  太晚了  回家吧
I don't want them to say, "Too late. It's full. Go back home."
我们定了位  借下光
Wait up. We've got a reservation! Leave some room for us!
看  人龙多长
Look at this line!
到了  我们定了位
Here we are! We made a reservation!
谢谢
Thank you!
需要帮助吗
May l help you?
必定有误会
There's been a mistake.
什么误会
What mistake?
我丈夫和儿子在那车上
My husband and son are on that train.
你丈夫叫什么
What's your husband's name?
Guido Orefice
Guido Orefice.
Orefice的儿子
Joshua Orefice...
Orefice的叔叔
and Eliseo Orefice
都在那节车上
are on that train too.
没有误会
There's no mistake.
我也要上那节车
I want to get on that train too.
准备好了
We're all ready.
起程吧
Send them off then.
起程
Go, leave!
回去吧  太太
Go back home, ma’am.
我想上车
I want to get on that train.
让我上车
Let me get on that train!
妈妈来了
Mom's here!
他们停下火车  让妈妈上来
They stopped the train to let Mom get on.
Eliseo叔叔
Uncle Eliseo.
看清楚没有  好玩吗  累吗
Are you happy? Did you see this place? Are you tired?
-我不喜欢火车  -我也不喜欢
- I didn't like the train. – Me, either.
我们会坐巴士回家
We'll take the bus back.
我们要坐巴士走  有座位的巴士
We're taking the bus back! The one with the seats in it!
-我对他们说了  -说得好
- I told them. - It's better.
看到了吗  井井有条
You see? It's all organized!
看到人龙了吗  大家得排队进去
Did you see that line? People are lined up to get inside!
人人都想进去
Everybody wants to get in!
他们在玩什么游戏
What game is this?
对了
That's it!
这是个游戏
It's that game where...
我们一起玩…
It's the game...
的游戏
We're all players.
玩游戏必须守规矩
It's all organized. The game is...
男人一边  女人一边
the men are over here, the women are over there.
还有军人  他们主持游戏
Then there's the soldiers. They give us our schedule.
很严厉  没那么简单的
It's hard, you know. It's not easy.
谁一犯错  谁就要回家去
lf somebody makes a mistake, they get sent right home.
就是说  你要很小心
That means you have to be very careful.
但你赢  你就得到奖品
But if you win, you get first prize!
什么奖
What's the prize?
头奖
First prize!
-坦克  -我已经有一辆了
- It's a tank. - I already have one.
这是辆真正的坦克
This one's a real tank!
闪闪新
Brand new!
真的坦克
Real?
真的  我本来不想告诉你
Yes! I didn't want to tell you.
叔叔去哪里了
Where's Uncle Eliseo going?
他属于另一组  大家分成组
He's on another team. It's all organized.
再见  叔叔
Bye, Uncle!
真正的坦克
A real tank.
看  没有骗你吧
What did l tell you?
顶瓜瓜
Fabulous!
环境一流
What a place!
快点  别让人霸占我们的地方
Hurry up or they'll steal our places.
我们订了床位  两张单人床
We've got a reservation. Two singles!
借一借
Coming through!
那是我们的
There's our place!
我们睡在一起
This is our bed. We'll sleep real close.
这里又脏又臭  我要到妈妈那里
It's ugly here. It smells. I want to be with Mommy.
我们会的
We will be!
我肚子饿
I'm hungry!
我们会有东西吃的
We'll eat!
他们都很凶  呼呼喝喝的
Plus they're really mean here! They yell!
他们不得不凶  人人都在争头奖
They yell because everybody wants first prize. They have to be tough.
我什么时候才能看到妈妈
Can l see Mommy?
游戏玩完就能了
When the game's over.
游戏什么时候玩完
When's it over?
你要得到一千分
You have to get a thousand points.
谁得到一千分  谁就有坦克
Whoever gets a thousand points wins a tank.
我不相信  我们有点心吃吗
I don't believe you. Are we getting a snack?
点心
A snack?
我去问问  这里都是熟人
Just ask. We're all friends here.
-看看谁来了  他叫什么  - Bartolomeo
- Look who's here. What's his name? - Bartolomeo.
问你点事儿
Let me ask you something.
那个派果酱面包的人来了没有
Did the guy who hands out the bread and jam already come by?
真倒霉  我们刚刚错过了
Darn it all! We missed him by a second!
但他会再来  对不对
He'll come back again though, won't he?
他会再来
He's coming back.
他在说什么?
What did he say?
他问谁懂德语
He asked if anyone speaks German.
他要解释营中规矩
He's going to explain the camp's rules.
-你懂德语吗  -不懂
- Do you speak German? - No.
既来之则安之  游戏开始吧
The game starts now. Whoever's here is here, whoever's not is not.
先得一千分就胜出
The first one to get a thousand points wins.
奖品是辆真坦克
The prize is a tank!
真是个幸运儿
Lucky him!
每天播音宣布谁领先
Every day we'll announce who's in the lead from that loudspeaker.
得最少分的人要在背后...
The one with the least points has to wear a sign saying "jackass"...
吊上个"蠢材"招牌
right here on his back.
我们士兵扮坏蛋  又呼又喝
We play the part of the real mean guys who yell.
谁害怕  谁得的分就少
Whoever's scared loses points.
在三个情况下  你们分数全失
You'll lose your points for three things.
一  哭
One, if you cry.
二  要找妈妈
Two, if you want to see your mommy.
三  肚饿要吃点心
Three, if you're hungry and you want a snack.
不要妄想
Forget about it!
肚饿很容易丢分
It's easy to lose points for being hungry.
昨天我丢了40分...
Just yesterday l lost 40 points...
因为我一定要吃果酱面包
because l absolutely had to have a jam sandwich.
杏酱面包
Apricot jam!
他要草莓酱的
He wanted strawberry.
棒棒糖你们不会有得吃
Don't ask for any lollipops. You won't get any.
统统给我们吃
We eat them all!
我昨天就吃掉20个
I ate 20 of them yesterday!
吃到我肚子痛
What a stomachache.
但确实美味
But they sure were good.
还用说吗
You bet.
说得太快了真抱歉  因为在玩捉迷藏
Sorry if I'm going so fast, but I'm playing hide and seek.
我要走了  否则就被抓到了
I have to go now or they'll find me.
有问题  问Bartolomeo  他通天晓地
Don't ask me anything. Ask Bartolomeo. He knows everything.
他说什么  别忘记告诉我
Don't forget to tell me what he said too.
一千分吗
A thousand points?
没骗你吧  真的好玩
I told you we're going to have fun!
这些人有病
These guys are crazy!
铁砧百公斤重  这里三千度热
This has to weigh a hundred kilos! It's got to be 3,000 degrees in here!
Vittorino  我捱不住
Vittorino, I can't cope anymore!
-搬一个就捱不住了  -还要搬啊
- After only the first one? - Why, are there more to move?
还要搬  搬到今晚
We're here until tonight!
Bartolomeo  他们带你去哪里?
Bartolomeo, what happened? Where are they taking you?
去医院  我胳膊受伤了
To the hospital. l hurt my arm.
我们死定了
We're going to die here!
我捱不住了  我要把它放下
I can't take it anymore! I'm putting this down.
我不做  他们会怎样
I'll tell them I can't do it. What can they do to me?
会杀掉你
They'll kill you!
-搬去哪里  -下面
- Where does this thing go? - Down there.
惨了  我死定了
Good Lord! I'll never make it!
这里肯定有一万度
It's got to be 1 0,000 degrees in here!
爸爸
Pop!
看  我的制服不错吧
Look here! See? It's nice, huh?
我们参加了
We're signed up.
我报名的时候
When I got there to sign up...
公证说...
the referee was there and he said...
名单上没有你两父子的名字
"No, you and your son aren't on the list.
你没有交报名费
You didn't pay your dues."
气得我差点晕过去
I almost fell over.
他说  你们回家吧  我说  你才回去呢
He said, "You can go home." l said, "No, you go home!
Joshua和我报了名
"Joshua and l signed up.
拿号码来
Give me my number!"
于是给了我一个号码
In fact, they gave me one. Look.
我叫他们印在胳膊上  万无一失
I had them put it here, too, just in case.
看  你爸爸...
See what a nice place...
带了你去一个顶瓜瓜的地方
your pop takes you to?
你有没有和其他孩子玩
Did you play with the other kids?
有  但他们不懂规矩
Yes, but they don't know the rules.
他们说头奖不是坦克
They said it isn't true that first prize is a tank.
也不懂得计分
They don't know anything about the points.
你不要相信他们  他们狡猾着呢
Did you fall for that? They're as sly as foxes.
他们想赢你  你不要相信
They want to beat you! Are you joking?
没有坦克  怎么可能
There's no tank? Don't you believe them!
我们今天得到几分
How many points did we get today?
Fifty.
48  他们扣了我两分
Forty-eight. They took two points away from me because...
因为我跳房子的时候...
I tripped while l was...
拌倒了
playing hopscotch.
我们今天玩得好开心
We laughed like crazy today! l died laughing!
认真过把瘾
Boy, did l have fun!
巴不得明天立即来到
I can't wait to start all over again tomorrow!
可以玩跳房子  拔河
Hopscotch, tug of war…
和团团转
and ring around the rosy.
游戏花款样多多  多到我想不起来
Every game. I don't even remember all of them.
我说  你们玩得太疯  累死我了
"You guys are obsessed! Stop! I'm tired!" I said.
Listen.
听着
有没有吃过东西
Did you eat something?
有  但我没要点心
Yes, but l didn't ask for a snack.
乖孩子  就是说你也得到了12分
Good boy! That means you got 12 points too!
我48  你12
Forty-eight for me, twelve for you.
一共60分
Sixty points.
60分你有奖
This is what you get when you get up to 60.
只是面包  没有果酱
A plain piece of bread, no jam.
吃吧
Here, eat this.
-60分多不多  -还用问吗
- Is 60 points a lot? - Are you kidding?
当然多
It sure is!
看谁来了  Bartolomeo
Look who's here! Bartolomeo!
情况怎样
How'd it go?
差点没命  我领了20
Any worse than this; l got 20 of them.
我们比他分高
We got more than him.
我们领先呢  别告诉他
Don't tell him that. We're in the lead!
我说过  小孩  老妪不准出来
I already told you: no children or old ladies!
回去  你不是劳动分子
Back inside! You don't work!
其他人  下楼去
The rest, downstairs!
快走吧  孩子们  这边去
Let's go, girls, quickly. Come on. This way!
这女兵一来就发狠
That one's new. She learned right away.
门口那女兵  初来时相当好相处
The lady at the door, she seemed nice when she first came.
现在变得最凶
She's the worst of all!
起码她不派老妇和小孩去劳动
At least she didn't send the old ladies and children to work.
老妇和小孩不用劳动  但要死
They don't send old people and kids to work because they kill them!
他们被派去洗澡
One of these days they'll call them to take a shower.
小朋友  洗澡啦
"Children, shower time!"
其实  去的是毒气室
The truth is, they make them shower there in the gas chamber.
下楼
Downstairs!
我怎捱得下去?
How can l do this?
Vittorino
Vittorino!
这些铁砧从哪里来
Where'd they find all these anvils?
爸爸
Pop!
你来干什么  你不应该来
Why are you here? You're not supposed to be here!
走开
Go away!
为什么不跟其他孩子一起呢
Why aren't you with the other kids?
他们说...
They said...
小孩今天都要洗澡  我不想洗
all us kids have to take a shower today, and l don't want to.
洗澡去吧
Go take a shower!
不去
No!
我就不去
I'm not going to.
给我洗澡去
Go take a shower!
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我们在制造...
We're making...
坦克
a tank.
我们正在制造  还没有造完坦克的轮带
We're building the tank. We're still working on the tracks.
我们做得太慢
We're running slow.
你不可以留在这里  去洗澡
You can't stay here. Go take your shower!
我不想洗
I don't want to!
小顽固  我会告诉你妈  扣你10分
You stubborn thing! I'll tell Mom! Ten points off for you!
在那里躲着  我下班  一同走
Hide behind there. We'll go back together when I'm done.
别让别人看到你
Don't let anyone see you!
这次可真够瞧的了
This sure is fun.
都脱光了
Everything!
全都脱光了  衣服挂在那儿
Take everything off! Hang it up there!
洗完澡可以拿回去
You'll get it back after the shower.
向前走
Forward!
记住自己的号码  方便认回衣服
Remember your number to get your clothes back!
妇女小孩一同洗澡
Women and children will shower together.
有没有跌伤
Are you hurt?
谢谢  Βartolomeo
Thanks, Βartolomeo.
以后你要整天躲在这里
From now on, you have to hide here the whole day.
被他们发现  我们就丧失资格啦
If they see us now it's over. We're disqualified.
我要做什么
What do I have to do?
你要留在这里  Vittorino  帮帮忙
You have to stay. Vittorino, help me out.
你一定要整天躲在这里
You have to hide here all day.
别让人见到  尤其呼喝的人
Don't let anyone see you, especially those mean guys who yell.
记着
Remember.
躲起来
Stay hidden!
这是游戏最难的部分了  如果玩得对...
This is the hardest part. If we get this right,
每天得120分  一定赢到坦克
the tank is ours. It's worth 120 points a day.
我会带你走  我会藏着你  大家都以为你失踪了
I'll take you with me. I'll hide you. You're gone.
以前谁见过你  你是谁  他在哪儿
Who's ever seen you before? Who are you? Where is he?
明白吗
Got it?
明白了
Got ya!
乖孩子
Good boy!
有没有人  我有没有打扰到你们
Anybody here? Am l disturbing?
过来
Come here!
我们要尽快
Quick as lightning!
早安  公主
Good morning, Princess!
昨晚...
Last night,
我整晚梦到你
I dreamt about you all night!
我们去看电影
We were going to the movies.
你穿着我喜欢的那套粉红套装
You were wearing that pink suit that I really like.
我脑中只有你  公主
You're all I think about, Princess.
惦念的只是你
I always think about you. And now...
妈妈
Mommy!
爸爸用轮车推我  但他不会推
Pop wheels me in the wheelbarrow, but he doesn't know how to drive!
笑到我肚子痛
We laugh like crazy!
我们领先呢  今天有得了多少分
We're in the lead! How many points do we have today?
快跑  呼喝的坏蛋在我们后面
Run! The mean guys who yell are behind us!
-哪里  -这里
- Where? - Over here! Come on!
衣服干了没有
Are they dry?
干了
They're dry.
接住
Catch.
穿上去
Get dressed.
Vittorino  Alfonso等人呢
What happened to Vittorino, Alfonso and the others?
他们活不成了
They didn't make it.
一提起我  我就消失
"If you say my name, I'm not there anymore."
沉默
Silence.
谢天谢地  吓死我了  什么事
Thank goodness. I was getting scared. What happened to you?
他们快疯了
They're half crazy!
替我检查那军医...
The man who does the check-ups, the Captain;
是我的朋友  我做侍者时认识
he's a friend of mine. l met him when l was a waiter.
他说  高官们和他们的妻子会举行晚宴
He said they're having a dinner with all the officials and their wives.
问我想不想去捧盘
He asked me if I wanted to wait tables at the dinner.
他或者有办法送我们出去
Maybe he wants to help me. He might get us out of here.
你看到Joshua了吗
Have you seen Joshua?
不知道  什么意思
What do you mean, no?
你在干什么  过来
What are you doing? Come here!
不
No.
叫你过来呢
l told you to come.
不  出来啊
No? Come on out!
看  你全身都弄脏了
Come out! Look here. You're all dirty.
你去了哪里
Where have you been?
我刚才在打纸牌
I had to finish playing rummy.
他们用我们做扣子  制肥皂
They make buttons and soap out of us.
什么
What are you saying?
他们把我们送入火炉烧死
They burn us all in the oven.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
有个人一边哭一边说...
A man was crying.
他们用我们做扣子  制肥皂
He said they make buttons and soap out of us.
你信了吗
You fell for that?
又信了
Again?
我还以为你是个精乖的小孩
I thought you were a sharp boy; cunning, intelligent.
用人来做扣子  制肥皂  怎可能
Buttons and soap out of people? That'll be the day!
你却相信
You believed that?
想想看  我用Bartolomeo变的肥皂洗手…
Just imagine. Tomorrow morning, l wash my hands with Bartolomeo...
真好用
a good scrub.
然后  扣Francesco变的扣子吗
Then I'll button up with Francesco.
有没有可能  你说
Darn it all!
Giorgio不见了
Look! l just lost Giorgio!
这颗纽扣像他吗
Does this look like a person?
他们戏弄你  你却信以为真
Come on! They were teasing you! And you fell for it!
他们还说了什么
What else did they tell you?
说我们会被送入火炉
That we get cooked in the oven.
活活烧死
They burn us up in the oven.
你也信了  他们说你就信吗
You fell for that too! You just eat everything up!
我听过用柴当燃料
I've heard of a wood oven...
没听过用人当燃料
but I've never seen a man oven before.
我是木头做的  抓这个律师去烧吧
"I'm made of wood!" "Take this lawyer!"
律师太湿  烧不着
"This lawyer doesn't burn. He's not dry enough.
只会冒烟
Look at that smoke!"
钮扣  肥皂  烧人
Buttons, soap, we get burned in the oven.
别开玩笑了
Let's be serious now.
我明天还要玩布袋竞赛呢
I have a bag race with the bad guys tomorrow.
我不玩了  要回家去
That's enough. I want to go home.
现在回去吗
Now?
现在回去
Right now.
现在下着雨  你会淋出病的
It's raining now. You'll come down with a terrible fever!
我不管  现在就走
I don't care. Let's go.
好  你非要走的话...
All right. If you want to go...
我们走  收拾行李
I'll get our stuff and we'll leave.
我们可以走
We can leave?
当然  他们可以逼人留下吗
Naturally. What do you think they do, force people to stay here?
好难
That'll be the day.
异想天开  我们说走就走
Wouldn't that be great? Let's go. We'll pack our bags...
收拾好行李就走
and get out of here.
可惜  我们在领先  却弃权
What a shame. We were in the lead. We're quitting. Off the list we go.
那辆真坦克会被其他孩子赢去
Some other kid will win the real tank.
已经没有其他孩子了  我是唯一的一个
There aren't any other kids. I'm the only one left.
已经没有孩子了吗  这里多着呢
There aren't any more kids? It's chock-full of them here!
在哪里
Where are they then?
都在躲着  绝不露面
They're all hiding. Nobody's supposed to see them.
-都在认真玩游戏  -我不明白
- This is a serious game! – I just don't get it.
我们拿到了多少分
How many points do we have?
差不多687分
Almost 687.
告诉过你一千次了
I told you a thousand times.
不过  既然要走就走吧
Let's go, though.
-我们本来会赢的...  -我们会赢吗
- We're winning, but if you want-- - We're winning?
我们在领先  早已经告诉你
We're first, l told you.
但你要退出  只好退出
But we'll quit if you want.
我昨天才看过积分表
I saw the chart yesterday. We'll go anyway, though.
拜拜  Bartolomeo  我和Joshua要走了
Bye, Bartolomeo. Joshua and I are leaving.
我们讨厌这地方
We're fed up here.
坦克已经造成
The tank is done. It's ready.
抹干净火嘴再开车
Clean the spark plugs off before you start it.
记得要拉开油门
Open the throttle...
否则大炮会卡住轮带
otherwise the cannon will get stuck with the tracks.
还有那支机枪  多么精致
And the gun. Did you see how nice it is? It came out beautiful!
开车前记得松刹闸
Lift the emergency brake off before you move!
我和他要走了
We're going.
Joshua要退出
Joshua wants to quit.
本来要开着坦克走的
We could have gone back with a tank soon,
现在却要坐巴士
but we'll take the bus today.
我和Joshua要走了  大家再见
Joshua and l are leaving. So long, everybody!
我们讨厌这地方
We're tired of this place.
走吧  否则赶不上巴士了
Let's go or we'll miss the bus.
走吧  Joshua
Let's go, Joshua.
我怕被雨淋湿  发高烧
It's raining. I'll come down with a terrible fever!
是我  爸爸呀
It's me, Pop!
我有重要的话跟你说
I have to tell you something important! Come here!
那小鬼头今早一直躲避我
That little rascal's been running away all morning.
-真的有小孩  -二千个
- Is there really a kid? - There must be two thousand!
他们像小老鼠  到处躲
They're like mice. They hide all over the place!
都想得到我们的坦克  停
Those creeps want our tank! Stop!
等一等
Wait.
我似乎见过他
I might have spotted him.
他可能在附近
I think he's nearby.
不如你去查一查  我在这里等
Look. Go see if he's hiding in there. I'll wait here.
替你把风
I'll keep a watch out.
他在那里  爸爸
He's there, Pop!
-什么样子的  金发吗  -嗯
- What'd he look like? Blond? - Yes.
正是他  他叫Schwanz
That's him then. His name is... Schwanz.
躲在里面已经三个星期了
He's been in there for three weeks.
他排第二  但我们领先
He was the runner up. We beat him, though!
迟早我会找到其他的孩子
Sooner or later, I'll find the others too.
-有多少个  -密密麻麻
- How many are there? - It's swarming, l told you.
都躲着
They're all hidden.
爸爸  看呀
Look, Pop!
这是个匿藏点
There's a hideout!
你  你  你  取消资格  我们走
Got ya, got ya, got ya! You're out! Let's go.
靠  她看见我们了
Holy smokes! She saw us!
我们被淘汰了吗
Are we out?
她过来是因为她看见了你
She's coming over for you.
现在玩沉默游戏
Now it's time for the "be quiet" game.
你绝对不要吱声
You're never to speak.
发誓
Swear it!
-发誓啊  -我发誓
- Swear it! – I swear.
他们咕噜咕噜  你反正听不懂
They all talk strange. You can't understand a word.
我们过得这关  头奖就是我们的了
If we get through this, the first prize is ours.
所有领先的人  都要玩沉默游戏
They're rounding up everyone in first place. It's the silence game.
一声都不能出  知道吗
Not a word, got it?
你为什么跟小孩在这里
Why are you here with the children?
不准你和孩子交谈
Quiet! You're never to speak.
我发誓不会
I swear.
我有话对你说  很重要
I have to talk to you. Very important.
-哪里  几时  -我会打暗号  过会儿
- Where? When? – I'll signal you. Later.
谢谢
Thank you.
我叫过你别跟小孩说话
I told you not to talk to the children.
医生  内子也在这里
Doctor, my wife is here too.
慢慢吃
Slowly.
吃得太快不好
Eat slowly. It's bad for you.
我们领先  可能早走
We're in the lead. We just might leave early.
游戏提早结束
The game finishes early.
我们要分外小心  不要出错
Don't make a mistake now that we're in the lead.
慢慢吃
Slowly.
留心听这个谜
So. Pay attention.
肥肥丑丑
"Fat, fat, ugly, ugly,
胆小到发黄
all yellow in reality.
你问我  我是什么家伙
If you ask me what I am...
我会答  贱贱贱
I answer, 'Cheep, cheep, cheep.'
我一面走路  一面拉弓
Walking along l go, 'Poopoo'.
我到底是谁
Who am I? Tell me true."
小鸭  对吗
A duckling, right?
是不是小鸭
Is it a duckling?
不是
It's not!
在维也纳的时候爸爸的一个兽医朋友出的这个谜面
A veterinarian friend of mine sent it to me from Vienna.
我猜不出来
I can't send him mine...
就不能还他一个谜面
until I solve this one.
我以为是...
I thought...
鸭嘴兽
duck-billed platypus...
但鸭嘴兽不叫  贱贱贱
but it doesn't go, "Cheep, cheep, cheep."
鸭嘴兽叫...
A duck-billed platypus goes...
昨晚我替你翻译成意大利话
I translated it into Italian for you last night.
你认为怎样
Well, what do you say?
除了小鸭  我想不出什么
Everything points to a duckling.
帮帮忙
Help me.
求求你
For heaven's sake...
帮帮忙
help me.
我连睡也睡不着
I can't even sleep.
谜底是小鸭
It's the duckling!
过来
Come here!
-我好累  -过来
- I'm tired. - Come here.
我们在哪里
Where are we here?
我可能走错了路
I might have taken the wrong way.
乖孩子  睡吧  做个美梦
Good boy, sleep. Dream sweet dreams.
可能现在就是个梦
Maybe it's only a dream!
我们在做梦  Joshua
We're dreaming, Joshua.
明早  妈妈会摇醒我们
Tomorrow morning, Mommy will come wake us up...
端来牛奶  饼干
and bring us two nice cups of milk and cookies.
我们先吃
First, we'll eat.
然后我跟她做两三次爱
Then I'll make love to her two or three times...
如果我还有气力
if I can.
对不起  Bartolomeo
Excuse me, Bartolomeo.
有两军官没有报到  我觉得他们溜掉了
They've called those two officers 20 times. l bet they escaped.
你还听懂什么
Did you understand anything else?
即使猜也猜得七七八八
It's clear enough.
快打完仗  纳粹党树倒猢狲散
The war is over. They're running all over the place.
货车要开到哪里
Where are those trucks going?
最要紧的是别坐上去
The important thing is not to get on those trucks.
满车去  空车回
They leave full and come back empty.
你知道车子开到哪里吗
You know where they're going?
女人呢  她们怎么了
What about the women? What's going on?
我们离开这地狱吧  各散东西
Let's get out of this dump and split up.
连行李也不用收拾
We don't even have to pack our bags!
枪声  狗吠  吵了好几个钟头
I've been hearing only dogs and machine guns.
他们想毁灭一切
They want to get rid of everything.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
我们在Viareggio再见  合作开铁砧厂
See you in Viareggio. We'll start an anvil factory!
再见了  各位  我走了
So long, guys. I'm leaving.
来看吧
Come see.
他们多生气  气得在跳
Look how mad they are! Furious!
看见了吗  都在找你
You see? They're looking for you.
这样大阵仗  只为了找你
Just for you. All this is over you!
你是最后一个  只剩下你
You're the last one! The last one to find!
他们拼命找  连石头也翻起来
They're even looking under the rocks!
游戏明早结束  举行颁奖典礼
The game is over tomorrow. They'll give the award.
你躲得过今晚  就得到60分
If they don't find you tonight, it's worth 60 points!
我们现在有几分
How many points do we have?
我们有940分  再加60呢
We've got 940 points. Plus 60?
-一千  -冠军  我们胜出
- A thousand! - First place! We win!
他们找遍每个角落也找不到你
They're looking all over for you.
今晚是最后一关  不要出错
No mistakes tonight. This is it!
-快躲在箱内   -Schwanz在里面
- Go hide in that box, quick! - Schwanz is in there.
谁
Who?
那个金发男孩
The blond boy.
他们昨天发现他  淘汰了
They got him yesterday. He was eliminated.
那处最安全  谁也不会再去找
It's the safest place to hide. Nobody will look.
走吧  快走
Let's go, quick as lightning. Come on!
进去
Inside!
带张毯  保暖
Take this blanket in case you get cold.
我很快回来
I'll be back soon.
我引开他们...  他在那边
I'll put them on the wrong track. I think I saw him over there!
爸爸  我被你吓死啦
Pop, you scared me to death!
那张毯给我  你冷吗
Give me the blanket. Are you cold?
把外衣也给我
Give me your sweater then.
我扔在树上  引开他们
I'll throw it on a tree and put them off track.
他们到处找你
They're looking all over for you!
大家都大喊  Joshua呢
Everybody's yelling, "Where's Joshua?"
破口大骂  来势汹汹
They're even cursing. They're really, really mad!
谁也不会找到你  我迟点回来
No one will find you. Bye, now. I'll be back later.
听着
Listen...
即使我很久才回来
if I'm really late coming back...
你也不要动
don't you move.
不要出来
Don't come out. You're not to come out...
直到一点声  一个人都没有
until it's completely quiet...
安全至上
and nobody is in sight, just to be safe.
说一遍
Say it!
我不出来  直到一个人都没有
I won't come out until nobody is around.
乖孩子  小顽固
Good boy, stubborn.
走开
Leave!
走开  狗
Go away, dog!
走开  你这只狗
Go, dog!
走开
Leave.
有你的  Ferruccio
Good job, Ferruccio.
你的办法真奏效!
It works.
这里有没有人叫Dora的
Is there anyone called Dora here?
Dora  你在吗  是我呀
Dora, are you here? It's Guido.
这里有人躲着  Dora在吗
I know someone is hiding here. Is there a Dora here?
Dora在吗  意大利人  我的太太
Is there a Dora here? She's Italian. She's my wife.
有  这里有个Dora
Yes, there's a Dora here.
Dora  是我啊
It's me, Dora!
不是她  还有没有别的Dora
It's not her! Is there another Dora?
你们一到外面就跳车
Jump out of the truck as soon as you can!
跳车  逃
Get off! Jump out!
真的坦克
It's true!
小朋友
Boy!
你一个人吗  你叫什么
You alone? What’s your name?
完全听不懂我的话吗
Can’t you understand at least a word of mine?
来  我载你一程
Come on, I’ll give you a drive!
上来
Come on in!
来...  我抱你
Here… Let me hug you in.
妈妈
Mommy!
这是我的经历
This is my story.
这是我父亲所作的牺牲
This is the sacrifice my father made.
这是我父亲赐我的恩典
This was his gift to me.
我们赢了
We won!
是的  我们赢了
Yes, we won!
一千分  好开心啊
A thousand points to laugh like crazy about!
我们得了冠军  坐坦克回家
We came in first! We're taking the tank home!
我们赢了
We won!